Guide to the League of Women Voters of Pullman Records 1950-1980
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
League of Women Voters of Pullman Records
1950-1980
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
Cage 557
League of Women Voters of Pullman (Pullman, Wash.)
7 Linear feet of shelf space 13 Boxes
Records of the Pullman Chapter of League of Women Voters consist primarily of subject files concerning various public issues.
League of Women Voters of Pullman, in Washington State, was organized in February 1950. In 1952 it became a chartered local league. Each year the League studies and acts on local, state and national governmental issues. The League may take a stand on an issue after careful study, but it never supports or opposes either political party or any candidates. Financial support comes from League programs, membership dues and contributions. In its first two years the League started a survey that focused on local issues. This study resulted in a pamphlet entitled "Know Your Town". In this pamphlet the League promoted greater community action. The goals have remained consistent with those ideas in subsequent years of activity.
Records of the Pullman Chapter of League of Women Voters consist primarily of subject files concerning various public issues. These files are made up of variety of memoranda, reports, and miscellaneous publications.
The records, which were largely unarranged upon receipt, have been arranged alphabetically by subject. The audio tapes follow the subject file sequence.
This collection is open and available for research use.
Lenna Harding, on behalf of the League of Women Voters of Pullman, donated the records to Washington State University Libraries in 1982.
League of Women Voters of Pullman Records, 1941-1992 (Cage 628)
Preliminary Guide to the League of Women Voters of Pullman Records, 1950-2019 (MSSM 078)
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Washington (State) -- Politics and government; Pullman (Wash.) -- History
Women -- Political activity -- Washington (State) -- Pullman -- Records and correspondence; Elections -- Washington (State); Voting -- Washington (State) -- Pullman; Suffrage -- Washington (State) -- Pullman; Election law -- Washington (State)
Women; Washington (State); Politics and Politicians
- Administration, 1962-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Alternatives for Washington: Government Commission, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Annual Reports, 1955-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Annual Reports, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Asian Studies Program, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Auditor's Report, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Beverage Container Price Control, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Board of Directors-Minutes, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Board Meetings Minutes/Annual Meetings, 1962-1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1967-1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Board Organization, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Bookkeeping Records, 1965-1978 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Bulletin of the League of Women Voters, 1967-1971 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- By-Laws, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Calendar, 1954-1978 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Census and Annual Reports, 1964-1965; 1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Child Care, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- City Planning: Commission, Facts and Information, 1957-1969 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Committee Guide, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Constitution, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Constitutional Convention, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Correspondence: Congressional, 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Correspondence: General, 1950-1963 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Correspondence: Local, 1965-1977 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Correspondence: State Legislature, 1968-1973 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Correspondence: State League of Women Voters, 1965-1976 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Directory of League Ladies in Local Office, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Discussion Techniques, 1964-1970 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- DPM-Memorandum U.S. League of Women Voters, 1964-1970 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Education, 1957-1979 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Energy Information, 1975-1980 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Equal Representation for Washington, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Equal Rights Amendment, 1976-1980 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Fiftieth Anniversary of the National LWV, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Financial Information, 1962-1974 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Foreign Policy-International Information, 1967-1979 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Grants, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Handbook of League of Women Voters, 1967-1973 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Handbook Material, 1957-1971 (Box 5, Folder 39)
- History of League of Women Voters, 1950-1980 (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Home Rule for Washington D.C., 1965 (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Human Resources-Environment, 1965-1971 (Box 6, Folder 42)
- Human Resources-Housing, 1962; 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 43)
- Human Resources-Solid Waste Treatment, 1971-1977 (Box 6, Folder 44)
- Indian Workshops, 1971-1974 (Box 6, Folder 45)
- Information from Nationals, 1968-1978 (Box 6, Folder 46)
- Internships, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 47)
- Juvenile Information, 1975-1978 (Box 6, Folder 48)
- Kindergarten Information, 1964-1966 (Box 6, Folder 49)
- Know Your Country, 1951-1980 (Box 6, Folder 50)
- Know Your Government, 1965-1976 (Box 6, Folder 51)
- Land Use, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 52)
- Lane Bryant Annual Awards, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 53)
- Leaders Handbook, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 54)
- League of Women Voters-Facts, 1965-1968 (Box 7, Folder 55)
- League of Women Voters-General, 1970-1979 (Box 7, Folder 56)
- Legislative Information, 1969-1976 (Box 7, Folder 57)
- Library Study, 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 58)
- Local Program Study, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 59)
- Members-Orientation, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 60)
- Membership-Fliers, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 61)
- Membership Lists-General Information, 1957-1979 (Box 7, Folder 62)
- Migratory Labor in the State of Washington, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 63)
- Minutes of the Board of Directors, 1951-1959 (Box 8, Folder 64)
- Miscellaneous: Congress, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 65)
- National Convention, 1968-1972 (Box 8, Folder 66)
- Other Leagues, 1968-1975 (Box 8, Folder 67)
- Optional Municipal Code, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 68)
- Orders through Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 8, Folder 69)
- Overseas Guests, 1961-1966 (Box 8, Folder 70)
- Planning Commission-Mobile Homes, 1961-1966 (Box 8, Folder 71)
- Planning Council-Whitman County, 1972-1979 (Box 8, Folder 72)
- Public Health Services: Whitman County, 1965-1979 (Box 8, Folder 73)
- Public Relations, 1970-1979 (Box 9, Folder 74)
- Publication Catalogs, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 75)
- Publications, 1968-1977 (Box 9, Folder 76)
- Pullman Flood Plan Studied, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 77)
- Pullman Redevelopment Committee, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 78)
- Pullman Task Force, 1971-1977 (Box 9, Folder 79)
- Recycling, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 80)
- Skits, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 81)
- State Board Reports, 1970-1973 (Box 9, Folder 82)
- State Board Reports, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 83)
- State Board Reports-Board Newletter, 1974-1978 (Box 10, Folder 84)
- State Board Visits, 1958-1980 (Box 10, Folder 85)
- State Conventions, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 86)
- State League Days, 1969-1973 (Box 10, Folder 87)
- State of Washington-LWV, 1959-1980 (Box 10, Folder 88)
- Study of the Principles of City, County and Regional Planning, 1961-1967 (Box 11, Folder 89)
- Surveys, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 90)
- Task Force Information: Water Pollution Control Act No. 28, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 91)
- Taxes-General Information, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 92)
- Testimony-Letters to Editors, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 93)
- Trade Caravan, 1970-1974 (Box 11, Folder 94)
- Transportation, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 95)
- Unit Organization, 1953-1964 (Box 11, Folder 96)
- United Nations, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 97)
- Urban Crisis, 1970-1978 (Box 11, Folder 98)
- The Voter-LWV Newsletter, 1957-1980 (Box 11, Folder 99)
- Voter's Services-Pullman and Whitman County, 1952-1972 (Box 12, Folder 100)
- Washington State and National Commission for Humanities, 1974-1976 (Box 12, Folder 101)
- Washington State Voter, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 102)
- Washington State Women's Council, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 103)
- Water Resources, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 104)
- Welfare Information, 1970-1980 (Box 12, Folder 105)
- Whitman County Government, 1971-1980 (Box 12, Folder 106)
- Woman and Law, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 107)
- Youth Outreach, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 108)
- Zoning Ordinance Proposal, undated (Box 12, Folder 109)
- Bulletins-Pullman LWV, 1955-1961 (Box 13, Folder 110)
- Bulletins-Pullman LWV, 1961-1967 (Box 13, Folder 111)
- Membership Receipts and Old Membership Lists, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 112)